<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>DNS Privacy Project on dnsprivacy.org</title>
    <link>http://dnsprivacy.org/</link>
    <description>Recent content in DNS Privacy Project on dnsprivacy.org</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 23 Jul 2021 10:48:37 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://dnsprivacy.org/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Zoom Breakout Room 1: Measurement of Encrypted DNS</title>
      <link>http://dnsprivacy.org/ndss_dns_privacy_workshop/2021_ndss_dns_privacy_workshop/workshop_notes/breakout_room_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jul 2021 10:41:57 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://dnsprivacy.org/ndss_dns_privacy_workshop/2021_ndss_dns_privacy_workshop/workshop_notes/breakout_room_1/</guid>
      <description>Zoom Breakout Room 1: Measurement of Encrypted DNS Kick-off question from Sandra: Who are we designing encrypted DNS protocols for? Idea from Benno (who couldn&amp;rsquo;t be present in the session): these protocols need to be designed to work for everybody. Alec: I don&amp;rsquo;t think &amp;ldquo;designing for everybody&amp;rdquo; would go well. DNS is a distributed protocol; it is a distributed database. It is very presumpuous of us to designate threat models onto third parties.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Call for Papers</title>
      <link>http://dnsprivacy.org/ndss_dns_privacy_workshop/2021_ndss_dns_privacy_workshop/call_for_papers/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jul 2021 10:17:40 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://dnsprivacy.org/ndss_dns_privacy_workshop/2021_ndss_dns_privacy_workshop/call_for_papers/</guid>
      <description>2021: NDSS DNS Privacy Workshop - Call for Papers The 2021 workshop was a virtual online conference held on 21st February 2021. Workshop on DNS Privacy: Measuring deployment and effectiveness of encrypted DNS. Submission link: https://dnspriv21.hotcrp.com/&#xA;Background The landscape around DNS Privacy has changed dramatically in the last few years, with tremendous developments in multiple areas. These include&#xA;Many new Internet Standards from the IETF primarily focussed on stub-to-recursive resolution privacy</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DNS-Over-TLS Patches</title>
      <link>http://dnsprivacy.org/project_notes/dns-over-tls_patches/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jul 2021 16:27:24 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://dnsprivacy.org/project_notes/dns-over-tls_patches/</guid>
      <description>Git repository TFO patches LDNS: ldns.1.6.17_dns-over-tls.patch Features Installation Unbound: unbound-1.5.1_t-dns.patch Features Installation NSD: nsd-4.1.0_dns-over-tls.patch Features Installation Git repository Patches are available here: https://portal.sinodun.com/stash/projects/TDNS/repos/dns-over-tls_patches/browse&#xA;STARTTLS is DNS is no longer described in any active draft, but is still available in these patches.&#xA;TFO patches Various TFO patches are provided - please see the TFO patch repository.&#xA;LDNS: ldns.1.6.17_dns-over-tls.patch Since this patches use TLS v1.2 a recent version of OpenSSL is required.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Initial Performance Measurements (Q1 2018)</title>
      <link>http://dnsprivacy.org/performance_measurements/initial_performance_measurements_q1_2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jul 2021 16:03:20 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://dnsprivacy.org/performance_measurements/initial_performance_measurements_q1_2018/</guid>
      <description>Initial work Nameservers Test setup Software Test parameters Hardware OS tuning Nameserver configuration Results Increasing load UDP only UDP vs TCP TCP vs TLS TCP and TLS as a percentage of UDP Vary queries per connection Less than 60,000 queries per connection Less than 10,000 queries per connection Less than 500 queries per connection Key conclusions TODO list Comments on test stability Thanks to funding from the Open Technology Fund we have started work on some performance measurements for various DNS Privacy implementations.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Comparison of policy and privacy statements 2019</title>
      <link>http://dnsprivacy.org/running_a_dns_privacy_server/best_current_practices/comparison_of_policy_and_privacy_statements_2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jul 2021 17:27:41 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://dnsprivacy.org/running_a_dns_privacy_server/best_current_practices/comparison_of_policy_and_privacy_statements_2019/</guid>
      <description>The goal of this page is to provide a high level overview of the operations and privacy policies and practices (as published in 2019) of some of the larger DNS Privacy service offerings. NOTE: An analysis of privacy statements by operators will clearly only provide a snapshot at the time of writing. The page content was last reviewed on 18th Dec 2019. Please email any corrections to sara@sinodun.com&#xA;Operators Operators Quad9 Cloudflare Google OpenDNS Comparison Policy Practice Quad9 UDP/TCP and TLS (port 853) service provided on two addresses:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Certificate management Method 1</title>
      <link>http://dnsprivacy.org/running_a_dns_privacy_server/lets_encrypt_certificate_renewal/automated_certificate_management_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jul 2021 17:02:51 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://dnsprivacy.org/running_a_dns_privacy_server/lets_encrypt_certificate_renewal/automated_certificate_management_1/</guid>
      <description>Background DNS setup CNAMES Configure dehydrated Create a domains file Write a hook script Write a script to download the certificates to your DNS servers Background At Sinodun we use dehydrated https://github.com/lukas2511/dehydrated to manage our certificates. Also we use the dns-01 challenge to renew them.&#xA;Since we run multiple DNS-over-TLS servers, the method used here employs a single &amp;lsquo;certificate management&amp;rsquo; server to renew the certificates, update the zone with the dns-01 challenge and make the renewed certificates available via ftp.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Building HAProxy using TLSv1.3</title>
      <link>http://dnsprivacy.org/running_a_dns_privacy_server/using_a_tls_proxy/building_haproxy_using_tlsv1_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jul 2021 14:16:09 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://dnsprivacy.org/running_a_dns_privacy_server/using_a_tls_proxy/building_haproxy_using_tlsv1_3/</guid>
      <description>Building HAProxy so that it can use TLSv1.3 This page gives an outline of how to build HAProxy with OpenSSL so it can use TLS v1.3. It assumes Ubuntu 16.04 as the platform. Build Openssl In order to have TLS 1.3 support you will need to grab version 1.1.1 of OpenSSL.&#xA;These instructions build OpenSSL into a directory /opt/openssl-1.1.1 to ensure that it&amp;rsquo;s separate to any other OpenSSL installs on the machine.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Using Unbound</title>
      <link>http://dnsprivacy.org/running_a_dns_privacy_server/using_unbound/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jul 2021 13:57:34 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://dnsprivacy.org/running_a_dns_privacy_server/using_unbound/</guid>
      <description>Use at least version 1.5.5 of Unbound if you want to configure your server with a certificate (as support for intermediate certificates was introduced in this version).&#xA;Version 1.6.7 or later is recommended.&#xA;Config file An example configuration file for Unbound that runs DNS-over-TLS on port 853 is below.&#xA;server: directory: &amp;#34;/etc/unbound&amp;#34; username: unbound chroot: &amp;#34;/etc/unbound&amp;#34; # logfile: &amp;#34;/etc/unbound/unbound.log&amp;#34; #uncomment to use logfile. pidfile: &amp;#34;/etc/unbound/unbound.pid&amp;#34; # verbosity: 1 # uncomment and increase to get more logging.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Linux From Source</title>
      <link>http://dnsprivacy.org/dns_privacy_daemon_-_stubby/installation/linux_from_source/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jul 2021 13:00:49 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://dnsprivacy.org/dns_privacy_daemon_-_stubby/installation/linux_from_source/</guid>
      <description>Build options Dependencies Download the getdns source Build the code Configuration Run Stubby from the command line Logging Test Stubby Modify your upstream resolvers Build options The Stubby code can be built either&#xA;as a submodule of getdns (see below) or standalone with libgetdns as a dependancy. Instructions for this are in the Stubby github repo https://github.com/getdnsapi/stubby Dependencies For the most minimal Stubby build, the dependencies are&#xA;libssl and libcrypto from the OpenSSL Project.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>About Stubby</title>
      <link>http://dnsprivacy.org/dns_privacy_daemon_-_stubby/about_stubby/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jul 2021 12:45:29 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://dnsprivacy.org/dns_privacy_daemon_-_stubby/about_stubby/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lsquo;Stubby&amp;rsquo; is an application that acts as a local DNS Privacy stub resolver (using DNS-over-TLS). Stubby encrypts DNS queries sent from a client machine (desktop or laptop) to a DNS Privacy resolver increasing end user privacy.&#xA;Stubby is developed by the getdns project, has it&amp;rsquo;s own github repo and issue tracker but dnsprivacy.org currently hosts the online documentation for Stubby .&#xA;FAQ What is Stubby?&#xA;ANSWER: Stubby runs as a daemon on the local machine sending DNS queries to resolvers over an encrypted TLS connections providing increased privacy for the user.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Map of test server locations</title>
      <link>http://dnsprivacy.org/test_servers/map_of_test_server_locations/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jul 2021 11:36:47 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://dnsprivacy.org/test_servers/map_of_test_server_locations/</guid>
      <description>The map below is an static image of the current DNS-over-TLS test server locations. We don&amp;rsquo;t show Quad9 on here because they run an anycast service (see their website for details).&#xA;The icons reflect the software being used:&#xA;Green pin: Unbound Pink pin: Knot Resolver Blue pin: TLS proxy in front of a nameserver Blue flag: Unknown </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Zoom Breakout Room 2: Civil Society, Usability and DNS</title>
      <link>http://dnsprivacy.org/ndss_dns_privacy_workshop/2021_ndss_dns_privacy_workshop/workshop_notes/breakout_room_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jul 2021 10:45:17 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://dnsprivacy.org/ndss_dns_privacy_workshop/2021_ndss_dns_privacy_workshop/workshop_notes/breakout_room_2/</guid>
      <description>Zoom Breakout Room 2: Civil Society, Usability and DNS 9 people joined the breakroom of Session 2: Civil Society, Usability and DNS&#xA;0-5 minutes: Gurshabad summarized the talks in the second session&#xA;5-10 minutes to cover the questions to the talks: All the questions were covered during the talks, no questions asked.&#xA;10-25 minutes: discussion&#xA;Discussion:&#xA;Q: Paul Syverson: what can be done to make balkanization itself costly at an ecosystem level, so protocols that might be resistant to being functional if set up for use in a private space?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2018 NDSS DNS Privacy Workshop</title>
      <link>http://dnsprivacy.org/ndss_dns_privacy_workshop/2018_ndss_dns_privacy_workshop/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jul 2021 10:01:56 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://dnsprivacy.org/ndss_dns_privacy_workshop/2018_ndss_dns_privacy_workshop/</guid>
      <description>2018 Topic: Increasing Usability and Decreasing Traceability 2018 Topic: Increasing Usability and Decreasing Traceability Location and Important Dates Agenda Technical Programme Committee Contact Location and Important Dates Workshop Location: San Diego, CA, USA&#xA;Workshop date: 18th Feb 2018 (co-located with NDSS 2018)&#xA;Submission deadline: 15th Dec 2017 anywhere-on-earth.&#xA;The Call for papers for the 2018 workshop has now closed.&#xA;Notifications and invitations to present at the workshop: 13th Jan 2018</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>TCP Fast Open</title>
      <link>http://dnsprivacy.org/project_notes/tcp_fast_open/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jul 2021 16:35:51 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://dnsprivacy.org/project_notes/tcp_fast_open/</guid>
      <description>References Patches Quick guide Message flow Implementation details Client side code changes Linux API OS X API Server side code changes Kernel Parameters Linux OS X FreeBSD On-the-wire Clients Servers References TCP Fast Open (TFO) mechanism is described in https://tools.ietf.org/html/rfc7413&#xA;Other considerations can be found in this white paper.&#xA;Patches TFO is currently available available on Linux (full implementation in 4.1), OS X 10.12 and server side will be available for FreeBSd 10/11.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Follow-Up Performance Measurements (Q4 2108)</title>
      <link>http://dnsprivacy.org/performance_measurements/follow-up_performance_measurements_q4_2108/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jul 2021 16:06:33 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://dnsprivacy.org/performance_measurements/follow-up_performance_measurements_q4_2108/</guid>
      <description>Thanks to funding from the Open Technology Fund we have continued work on some performance measurements for various DNS Privacy implementations. We report our new results below.&#xA;Previous work Goals of this work Results - TCP vs UDP Unbound measurements Knot Resolver and BIND dnsdist Results - TLS proxy vs native TLS HA-Proxy fronting Unbound Limitations of these measurements Real DNS traffic data HTTP-like client population modelling? Previous work Our initial work on performance measurements can be found here: Initial Performance Measurements (Q1 2018).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Data minimisation of DNS traffic</title>
      <link>http://dnsprivacy.org/running_a_dns_privacy_server/best_current_practices/data_minimisation_of_dns_traffic/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jul 2021 17:34:05 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://dnsprivacy.org/running_a_dns_privacy_server/best_current_practices/data_minimisation_of_dns_traffic/</guid>
      <description>Terminology History Notable pseudonymising techniques Google Analytics non-prefix filtering dnswasher Prefix-preserving map Cryptographic Prefix-Preserving Pseudonymisation Top-hash Subtree-replicated Anonymisation ipcipher Bloom filters Other data minimisation considerations References The DNS Privacy solutions presented here ensure that DNS queries made by an individual end user can&amp;rsquo;t be observed by eavesdroppers as they pass across the Internet. Only the operators of DNS privacy servers have access to the details of the queries. For operational reasons such as monitoring server performance or detecting and mitigating attacks operators need to keep logs of the DNS queries they see; in some circumstances they may need to share those logs with other operators.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Certificate management method 2</title>
      <link>http://dnsprivacy.org/running_a_dns_privacy_server/lets_encrypt_certificate_renewal/automated_certificate_management_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jul 2021 17:06:39 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://dnsprivacy.org/running_a_dns_privacy_server/lets_encrypt_certificate_renewal/automated_certificate_management_2/</guid>
      <description>This page is assumes using OpenDNSSEC to sign zones. Thanks to Willem Toorop and Ralph Dolmans at NLnet Labs for developing this automated solution!&#xA;An example configuration file is:&#xA;CA=&amp;#34;https://acme-v01.api.letsencrypt.org/directory&amp;#34; #CA=&amp;#34;https://acme-staging.api.letsencrypt.org/directory&amp;#34; LICENSE=&amp;#34;https://letsencrypt.org/documents/LE-SA-v1.1.1-August-1-2016.pdf&amp;#34; CERTDIR=/usr/local/etc/dehydrated/certs CHALLENGETYPE=&amp;#34;dns-01&amp;#34; HOOK=/usr/local/etc/dehydrated/dnshook.sh PRIVATE_KEY_RENEW=&amp;#34;no&amp;#34; PRIVATE_KEY_ROLLOVER=&amp;#34;no&amp;#34; CONTACT_EMAIL=alice@example.com Private keys are then stored in&#xA;/usr/local/etc/dehydrated/certs/&amp;lt;domain&amp;gt;/privkey.pem The SubjectAltNames are then enumerated in the file&#xA;/usr/local/etc/dehydrated/domains.txt Add one line in this for each &amp;lsquo;group&amp;rsquo; of names that should share a certificate e.g</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Using Knot Resolver</title>
      <link>http://dnsprivacy.org/running_a_dns_privacy_server/using_knot_resolver/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jul 2021 14:01:03 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://dnsprivacy.org/running_a_dns_privacy_server/using_knot_resolver/</guid>
      <description>Config file An example configuration file for Knot that runs DNS-over-TLS on port 853 is below.&#xA;-- Default empty Knot DNS Resolver configuration in -*- lua -*- -- Bind ports as privileged user (root) -- -- net = { &amp;#39;127.0.0.1&amp;#39;, &amp;#39;::1&amp;#39;, net.ens160 } net.tls(&amp;#39;/etc/sinodun/certs/fullchain.pem&amp;#39;,&amp;#39;/etc/sinodun/certs/privkey.pem&amp;#39;) net.listen(&amp;#39;::&amp;#39;, 853) net.listen(&amp;#39;145.100.185.17&amp;#39;, 853) -- Switch to unprivileged user -- user(&amp;#39;knot-resolver&amp;#39;,&amp;#39;knot-resolver&amp;#39;) -- Unprivileged -- cache.size = 100*MB -- verbose(true) If you are using systemd with socket-based activation you need to remove the net.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Running as a service on *nix</title>
      <link>http://dnsprivacy.org/dns_privacy_daemon_-_stubby/installation/running_as_a_service_on_nix/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jul 2021 13:06:18 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://dnsprivacy.org/dns_privacy_daemon_-_stubby/installation/running_as_a_service_on_nix/</guid>
      <description>systemd upstart rc systemd There is basic support for using stubby with systemd. See the systemd directory. Also see the discussion on this issue.&#xA;upstart We have a contributed upstart script here.&#xA;rc There is an issue open requesting an rc.d script.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Configuring Stubby</title>
      <link>http://dnsprivacy.org/dns_privacy_daemon_-_stubby/configuring_stubby/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jul 2021 12:47:39 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://dnsprivacy.org/dns_privacy_daemon_-_stubby/configuring_stubby/</guid>
      <description>Create Custom Configuration File DNSSEC Storage of Zero-config Trust anchor Opportunistic DoT to your local resolver Runtime logging It is recommended to use the default configuration file provided which will use &amp;lsquo;Strict&amp;rsquo; privacy mode and spread the DNS queries among several of the current DNS Privacy test servers. Note that this file contains both IPv4 and IPv6 addresses.&#xA;Note also that this file only enables a small subset of the available servers by default.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>dnsprivacy Monitoring</title>
      <link>http://dnsprivacy.org/test_servers/monitoring/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jul 2021 11:53:47 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://dnsprivacy.org/test_servers/monitoring/</guid>
      <description>The URL for the DNS Privacy monitoring has changed - please update your bookmarks!&#xA;Visit the DNS Privacy Monitoring site</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Live Traffic Levels</title>
      <link>http://dnsprivacy.org/test_servers/live_traffic_levels/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jul 2021 11:53:47 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://dnsprivacy.org/test_servers/live_traffic_levels/</guid>
      <description>This service is temporarily offline</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Zoom Breakout Room 3: Novel Work, ADoT and Future Research</title>
      <link>http://dnsprivacy.org/ndss_dns_privacy_workshop/2021_ndss_dns_privacy_workshop/workshop_notes/breakout_room_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jul 2021 10:48:37 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://dnsprivacy.org/ndss_dns_privacy_workshop/2021_ndss_dns_privacy_workshop/workshop_notes/breakout_room_3/</guid>
      <description>Zoom Breakout Room 3: Novel Work, ADoT and Future Research Benno&amp;rsquo;s summary&#xA;Liang&amp;rsquo;s talk - IP address encryption as a complement to DOH or DOT, no change to DNS, no changes on endpoints. Can we get privacy benefit from this&#xA;Scott&amp;rsquo;s talk and DKG&amp;rsquo;s talk - there&amp;rsquo;s information leaked above recursive, but Scott asks if it&amp;rsquo;s operationally feasible for the auth operator to do encryption, whereas DKG takes the view that it needs to be</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2017 NDSS DNS Privacy Workshop</title>
      <link>http://dnsprivacy.org/ndss_dns_privacy_workshop/2017_ndss_dns_privacy_workshop/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jul 2021 09:56:39 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://dnsprivacy.org/ndss_dns_privacy_workshop/2017_ndss_dns_privacy_workshop/</guid>
      <description>Programme The official programme and remote participation details can be found on the conference website:&#xA;https://www.ndss-symposium.org/ndss2017/dns-privacy-workshop-2017-programme/&#xA;Agenda All times are PST.&#xA;Session (Time) Speaker Paper 1: Privacy Protocols&#xA;(9:00-10:15)&#xA;Laura M. Roberts Invited Talk: How DNS Works in Tor &amp;amp; Its Anonymity Implications (slides) (paper) Christian Huitema DNS Privacy through Mixnets and Micropayment (slides) Christian Grothoff Towards Secure Name Resolution on the Internet (slides) (paper) 2: The Leaky DNS Boat</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Try DNS-Over-TLS</title>
      <link>http://dnsprivacy.org/project_notes/try_dns-over-tls/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jul 2021 16:38:54 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://dnsprivacy.org/project_notes/try_dns-over-tls/</guid>
      <description>If you want to try out DNS-over-TLS then instructions are listed below.&#xA;Alternatively&#xA;Use Stubby as your local DNS-over-TLS resolver watch a short video demonstrating TCP connection re-use, pipelining, TCP Fast Open and DNS-over-TLS: DNS-over-TLS demo video Try DNS-over TLS Grab a DNS-over-TLS client tool: Grab the latest version of getdns or Grab the patch to ldns-1.6.17 https://portal.sinodun.com/stash/projects/TDNS/repos/dns-over-tls_patches/browse/ldns-1.6.17_dns-over-tls.patch Query a public NSD server patched to support DNS-over-TLS: Verisign Labs are kindly hosting a zone on a server running NSD patched to support DNS-over-TLS for testing purposes.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review of DNS and HTTP PM Tools</title>
      <link>http://dnsprivacy.org/performance_measurements/review_of_dns_and_http_pm_tools/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jul 2021 16:09:40 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://dnsprivacy.org/performance_measurements/review_of_dns_and_http_pm_tools/</guid>
      <description>Survey of existing DNS tools Investigation of HTTP benchmarking tools Survey Work on Tsung Survey of existing DNS tools Tool UDP TCP TLS Pipelining Uses query file Replay pcaps Comments dnsperf from DNS-OARC Y N N N Y N https://github.com/DNS-OARC/dnsperf resperf from DNS-OARC Y N N N Y N For testing resolvers&#xA;https://github.com/DNS-OARC/dnsperf&#xA;dnsperf-tcp Y Y N Y Y N https://github.com/Sinodun/dnsperf-tcp dnsperf-tls Y Y Y Y Y N https://github.com/Sinodun/dnsperf-tcp/tree/feature/tls_openssl. A re-factor was required to accomodate TLS usage within the threading model used here and we believe this introduces a performance overhead at very low queries per connection (below 500).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Using dnsdist</title>
      <link>http://dnsprivacy.org/running_a_dns_privacy_server/using_dnsdist/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jul 2021 14:07:34 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://dnsprivacy.org/running_a_dns_privacy_server/using_dnsdist/</guid>
      <description>Below is a simple configuration for setting up dnsdist as a server offering both DoT and DoH&#xA;addACL(&amp;#39;0.0.0.0/0&amp;#39;) addACL(&amp;#39;::/0&amp;#39;) addLocal(&amp;#39;0.0.0.0:53&amp;#39;,{doTCP=true, reusePort=true, tcpFastOpenSize=X}) -- for dns over port 53 ipv4 , set X(int) for tcp fast open queue size addLocal(&amp;#39;[::]:53&amp;#39;, {doTCP=true, reusePort=true, tcpFastOpenSize=X}) -- for dns over port 53 ipv6 , set X(int) for tcp fast open queue size addTLSLocal(&amp;#34;0.0.0.0&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;/Path/fullchain.pem&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;/Path/privkey.pem&amp;#34;,{ doTCP=true, reusePort=true, tcpFastOpenSize=X }) -- path for certs and listen address for DoT ipv4 , by default listens on port 853.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MacOS Homebrew</title>
      <link>http://dnsprivacy.org/dns_privacy_daemon_-_stubby/installation/macos_homebrew/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jul 2021 13:09:29 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://dnsprivacy.org/dns_privacy_daemon_-_stubby/installation/macos_homebrew/</guid>
      <description>Installation Running Stubby on the command line Logging from the stubby service Test Stubby Running Stubby as a service Modify your upstream resolvers Configuring stubby The Homebrew formula currently installs the 0.4.0 version of stubby, based on libgetdns 1.6.1&#xA;See this issue for details of problems with homebrew on BigSur: https://github.com/getdnsapi/stubby/issues/272#issuecomment-738622312&#xA;Installation 1. Install Homebrew if you don&amp;rsquo;t aleady have it:&#xA;/usr/bin/ruby -e &amp;#34;$(curl -fsSL https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Homebrew/install/master/install)&amp;#34; 2. Install stubby</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Stubby Manager GUI</title>
      <link>http://dnsprivacy.org/dns_privacy_daemon_-_stubby/stubby_manager_gui/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jul 2021 12:50:54 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://dnsprivacy.org/dns_privacy_daemon_-_stubby/stubby_manager_gui/</guid>
      <description>Latest release is 0.4.0-a2 (11-Dec 2020) Background Status Installation Overview Welcome page On/Off button Network Profiles Untrusted Trusted Hostile Networks Utilities Logs Code Bug reports and feature requests Future features Latest release is 0.4.0-a2 (11-Dec 2020) Background The Stubby Manager project is designed to provide a Graphical User Interface to manage Stubby aimed at both non-technical and advanced users. It will initially be supported on Windows only, macOS support will be added later.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DNS Privacy Services</title>
      <link>http://dnsprivacy.org/project_notes/dns_privacy_services/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jul 2021 16:40:56 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://dnsprivacy.org/project_notes/dns_privacy_services/</guid>
      <description>A number of organisations have expressed interest in running experimental public DNS Privacy servers. At the moment this page just attempts to capture the different features/characteristics that a DNS Privacy server can offer in more detail that the overview here: DNS Privacy Implementation Status&#xA;The intension in future is to document what each service actually offers as it goes live, to allow users to make informed choices about which service they might utilise.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Proposal for New Performance Tool</title>
      <link>http://dnsprivacy.org/performance_measurements/proposal_for_new_performance_tool/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jul 2021 16:12:21 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://dnsprivacy.org/performance_measurements/proposal_for_new_performance_tool/</guid>
      <description>Tool requirements High level Support multiple protocols by design including session based protocols. (Initial wish list is UDP, TCP, TLS, HTTPS and QUIC)&#xA;Support emulating ~30,000 clients on a single server/VM&#xA;Support configuration to describe client populations e.g.&#xA;10% of clients send at maximum rate the connection can sustain 50% send at X qps and use 2s idle timeout 40% send at Y qps use 10s idle timeout Read query names from a file or autogenerate them based on a simple algorithm</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Stubby GUI for macOS</title>
      <link>http://dnsprivacy.org/dns_privacy_daemon_-_stubby/installation/stubby_gui_for_macos/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jul 2021 13:39:32 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://dnsprivacy.org/dns_privacy_daemon_-_stubby/installation/stubby_gui_for_macos/</guid>
      <description>** THIS PROJECT IS NO LONGER MAINTAINED. WORK ON A NEWER STUBBY MANAGER GUI IS IN PROGRESS, SEE Stubby Manager GUI ** An installer package for an alpha release of the StubbyManager GUI App is now available:&#xA;This is the 0.2.6 of the prototype Stubby GUI. It is still very much a work in progress and has only very basic functionality! It is being released at this stage to gain feedback and review from users.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Google&#39;s Public DNS-Over-HTTPS</title>
      <link>http://dnsprivacy.org/project_notes/googles_public_dns-over-https/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jul 2021 16:43:16 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://dnsprivacy.org/project_notes/googles_public_dns-over-https/</guid>
      <description>On April 1st 2016 Google announced a Public DNS-over-HTTPS service:&#xA;https://developers.google.com/speed/public-dns/docs/dns-over-https#introduction&#xA;The API is only a beta and whilst not based on a standard, any public server that offers encrypted DNS to users is a good thing. But note that there is an active I-D in the general area of DNS-over-HTTP:&#xA;https://datatracker.ietf.org/doc/draft-song-dns-wireformat-http/&#xA;Our understanding is that this service was made available as a convenient web interface to test DNS queries, and potentially for use in some lightweight applications.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Windows installer for Stubby</title>
      <link>http://dnsprivacy.org/dns_privacy_daemon_-_stubby/installation/windows_installer_for_stubby/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jul 2021 13:41:48 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://dnsprivacy.org/dns_privacy_daemon_-_stubby/installation/windows_installer_for_stubby/</guid>
      <description>Overview Installation Latest stable msi and zip installers: Latest development msi and zip installers: Release notes Version 0.4.4-rc1 Version 0.4.0-a2 Version 0.4.0-a1 Version 0.3.0 Version 0.2.6 Version 0.2.5 Installer contents Configuration Run Stubby Test Stubby Modify your upstream resolvers Modify your upstream resolvers (Windows 7) Install Stubby as Windows service Create a Scheduled Task Known Issues Manual update of system revolvers on Windows Opportunistic mode Overview Stubby can be installed</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Monitoring Privacy servers</title>
      <link>http://dnsprivacy.org/running_a_dns_privacy_server/monitoring_privacy_servers/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jul 2021 17:12:19 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://dnsprivacy.org/running_a_dns_privacy_server/monitoring_privacy_servers/</guid>
      <description>DNS-over-TLS If you want to monitor the TLS specific or DNS Privacy specific features of a recursive server then there are a couple of options:&#xA;A new tool getdns_server_mon is being developed which will provide output in both human readable and Nagios API compatible form. This tool was included in the 1.4.0 release of getdns. This tool is used on the dnsprivacy.org test server monitoring page. Stephane Bortzmeyer developed a standalone plugin based on getdns which inspired the above tool.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
