<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Workshop Notes on dnsprivacy.org</title>
    <link>http://dnsprivacy.org/ndss_dns_privacy_workshop/2021_ndss_dns_privacy_workshop/workshop_notes/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Workshop Notes on dnsprivacy.org</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 23 Jul 2021 10:48:37 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://dnsprivacy.org/ndss_dns_privacy_workshop/2021_ndss_dns_privacy_workshop/workshop_notes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Zoom Breakout Room 1: Measurement of Encrypted DNS</title>
      <link>http://dnsprivacy.org/ndss_dns_privacy_workshop/2021_ndss_dns_privacy_workshop/workshop_notes/breakout_room_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jul 2021 10:41:57 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://dnsprivacy.org/ndss_dns_privacy_workshop/2021_ndss_dns_privacy_workshop/workshop_notes/breakout_room_1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;zoom-breakout-room-1-measurement-of-encrypted-dns&#34;&gt;Zoom Breakout Room 1: Measurement of Encrypted DNS&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Kick-off question from Sandra: Who are we designing encrypted DNS&#xA;protocols for?&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Idea from Benno (who couldn&amp;rsquo;t be present in the session): these&#xA;protocols need to be designed to work for everybody.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Alec: I don&amp;rsquo;t think &amp;ldquo;designing for everybody&amp;rdquo; would go well. DNS&#xA;is a distributed protocol; it is a distributed database. It is&#xA;very presumpuous of us to designate threat models onto third&#xA;parties. Telling users how much privacy they are allowed to have&#xA;(i.e., the security/privacy properties of encrypted DNS&#xA;protocols) will inevitable have consequences. It may drive them&#xA;underground.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Sandra: I agree, but most people don&amp;rsquo;t know what DNS is, nor&#xA;DoT/DoH. They don&amp;rsquo;t necessarily know what decisions to make.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Paul: Historically, the IETF has been pretty bad at predicting&#xA;user behavior. The development of the Internet in general has&#xA;shown that every new protocol has been bent (and that may be one&#xA;of the charms of the Internet!) There&amp;rsquo;s clearly a need for&#xA;better education. The best we can do right now is &amp;ldquo;turn loose&amp;rdquo; a&#xA;bunch of stuff (e.g., protocols) and see what sticks.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Paras: Until now, every presentation I&amp;rsquo;ve heard on encrypted DNS&#xA;has been about how to get the lowest latency. Alec, I like that&#xA;your presentation doesn&amp;rsquo;t just focus on getting the lowest&#xA;latency, but rather something that&amp;rsquo;s acceptable. However, I have&#xA;kids in my house, and they&amp;rsquo;re really impatient. If I ask my 13&#xA;y/o, they just want the fastest protocol; they&amp;rsquo;re not as&#xA;concerned about privacy. Thus, the decisions we make about&#xA;protocols and tradeoffs between latency/privacy are very&#xA;individualistic.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Alec: In my experience, waiting for Netflix with DoHoT is not&#xA;too bad. It&amp;rsquo;s no worse than using 4G in a well-served area.&#xA;Occasionally, you go through days where there&amp;rsquo;s extra latency&#xA;for a brand new domain name that isn&amp;rsquo;t cached, but otherwise&#xA;that&amp;rsquo;s lost in the noise. I can&amp;rsquo;t speak for your kid, but I&amp;rsquo;m&#xA;just happy to make something that just works. I want to make the&#xA;point that latency is a budget, not a cost.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Simone: Because of my work with OONI, I spend a lot of time&#xA;speaking with users not in the West. I am humbled by the amount&#xA;of information these people have about censorship, and how to&#xA;circumvent it, e.g. with DoT/DoH/VPNs. They know this out of&#xA;necessity. I believe that on the one hand saying that users are&#xA;&amp;ldquo;dumb&amp;rdquo; is true to an extent, but we have to qualify this&#xA;statement. Increasingly, this is not becoming the case. Who am I&#xA;designing for: everyone where &amp;ldquo;everyone&amp;rdquo; means people that have&#xA;difficulties using it. I would encourage us to design stuff that&#xA;considers everyone in the world.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Sudheesh: I did not mean to say that users are &amp;ldquo;dumb.&amp;rdquo; I agree&#xA;with the idea that latency and performance are not everything.&#xA;There are a huge number of people that don&amp;rsquo;t even have cellular&#xA;connectivity. However, we can&amp;rsquo;t neglect the idea that latency&#xA;and performance matter. The goal should be to drive down latency&#xA;while increasing connectivity and increasing security/privacy.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Alec: Imagine you worked for a really large social network. They&#xA;have to deal with the fact that people have satellite links, and&#xA;people are joining the network from less well-connected&#xA;networks. You may want to build caches that are close to these&#xA;users. Why not, then, address the question of making DNS fast&#xA;for everyone by having a &amp;ldquo;local&amp;rdquo; version of ODoH (or DoHoT) that&#xA;works in local networks, rather than a centralized solution?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Zoom Breakout Room 2: Civil Society, Usability and DNS</title>
      <link>http://dnsprivacy.org/ndss_dns_privacy_workshop/2021_ndss_dns_privacy_workshop/workshop_notes/breakout_room_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jul 2021 10:45:17 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://dnsprivacy.org/ndss_dns_privacy_workshop/2021_ndss_dns_privacy_workshop/workshop_notes/breakout_room_2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;zoom-breakout-room-2-civil-society-usability-and-dns&#34;&gt;Zoom Breakout Room 2: Civil Society, Usability and DNS&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;9 people joined the breakroom of Session 2: Civil Society, Usability and&#xA;DNS&lt;br&gt;&#xA;0-5 minutes: Gurshabad summarized the talks in the second session&lt;br&gt;&#xA;5-10 minutes to cover the questions to the talks: All the questions were&#xA;covered during the talks, no questions asked.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;10-25 minutes: discussion&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Discussion:&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Q: Paul Syverson: what can be done to make balkanization itself costly&#xA;at an ecosystem level, so protocols that might be resistant to being&#xA;functional if set up for use in a private space? That is clearly in&#xA;great tension to modular design and testing. (Easy narrow question what&#xA;can be done to make&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Ram: If we look at the top alexa companies, most of them are based on US&#xA;and EU. It&amp;rsquo;s important to let people access these companies. CDN could&#xA;be an option as the CDN points cannot be blocked.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Gurshabad: even the govt needs access to these endpoints, like CDN. the&#xA;externality of consolidation is that it is disincentive for&#xA;balkanisation.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Ulrich Wisser: A country can do whatever they can, we can&amp;rsquo;t stop that,&#xA;we need to make one to participate. what is one&amp;rsquo;s incentive to stay&#xA;on?&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Vijay: China and Russian applies a lot of censorship. It&amp;rsquo;s hard to find&#xA;a resolution for such countries.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Ram: if the protocol can consider the censorship when it is designed and&#xA;standardized, it might be hard for the countries to block&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Gurshabad: TLS 1.3 is not usually blocked (because of critical mass)&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Ram: you need TLS 1.3 to protect the internet, but it&amp;rsquo;s not true for Dot&#xA;and DoH&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Vijay: it&amp;rsquo;s easy to port 853, but it&amp;rsquo;s hard to block 443. It&amp;rsquo;s hard to&#xA;change how a big country applies their censorship.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Han: even we add consideration of censorship in protocol, a country may&#xA;run their own protocol within the country and translate the protocol to&#xA;the standard one on the country edge. But we can make the protocol&#xA;conversion hard.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Zoom Breakout Room 3: Novel Work, ADoT and Future Research</title>
      <link>http://dnsprivacy.org/ndss_dns_privacy_workshop/2021_ndss_dns_privacy_workshop/workshop_notes/breakout_room_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jul 2021 10:48:37 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://dnsprivacy.org/ndss_dns_privacy_workshop/2021_ndss_dns_privacy_workshop/workshop_notes/breakout_room_3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;zoom-breakout-room-3-novel-work-adot-and-future-research&#34;&gt;Zoom Breakout Room 3: Novel Work, ADoT and Future Research&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Benno&amp;rsquo;s summary&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Liang&amp;rsquo;s talk - IP address encryption as a complement to DOH or DOT, no&#xA;change to DNS, no changes on endpoints. Can we get privacy benefit from&#xA;this&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Scott&amp;rsquo;s talk and DKG&amp;rsquo;s talk - there&amp;rsquo;s information leaked above&#xA;recursive, but Scott asks if it&amp;rsquo;s operationally feasible for the auth&#xA;operator to do encryption, whereas DKG takes the view that it needs to&#xA;be&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Open discussion -&amp;gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;DKG asks Scott about the TLS vulnerabilities:&lt;br&gt;&#xA;are they vulnerabilities to the operation or to the cryptographic&#xA;promise of TLS? Characterize the attack service better for authoritative&#xA;servers considering deployment&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Scott says - we didn&amp;rsquo;t dig deep into this. Different vulns have&#xA;different risks. This is a place where studies are important.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Benno - Scott, you did an analysis and a handful of others did - is&#xA;there an overview of the operational impacts studies? Who should be&#xA;doing this? Where should this information be shared?&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Scott - has some things happening along those lines - we do protocol&#xA;design in the IETF, but not how it really works. IF we make a mistake in&#xA;ops for COM, NET, A and J roots, that&amp;rsquo;s very bad. Scott will be talking&#xA;about this during upcoming DNSSEC Workshop at ICANN. These aren&amp;rsquo;t going&#xA;to be resolved in the IETF, needs to be where the operators are.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Allison - there are many types of SLD. My org is talking with our&#xA;vendors - we have different tradeoffs than a TLD or an infrastructure&#xA;SLD&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Scott - characterized the enterprise domains as smaller or lower risk&lt;br&gt;&#xA;DKG points out that you could safely try at root and TLDs too by having&#xA;some instances&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Jim Reid - don&amp;rsquo;t forget that if enterprise domains are broken, there are&#xA;also some dire consequences. A lot of ISPs or others will think it&amp;rsquo;s too&#xA;hard and it will result in more aggregation and consolidation - toss it&#xA;to Google or another third party&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Wes Hardaker - didn&amp;rsquo;t write down this question&amp;hellip;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Paul Hoffman - just to be clear, from my comments in the main session,&#xA;I&amp;rsquo;m very hesitant for us to say that &amp;ldquo;in order to get to this place,&#xA;these people must do something&amp;rdquo; - we should not link privacy decisions&#xA;to someone doing enough of what&amp;rsquo;s needed. Just don&amp;rsquo;t assume that the&#xA;resolver operators will do the right thing. Even qname minimization is&#xA;still dicey and experimental. If we want more privacy, offering many,&#xA;letting people try it, find out how it works by measuring it. Don&amp;rsquo;t&#xA;discourage anyone to try what works for their need. We know there are&#xA;TLDs that care a great deal to be very privacy preserving. He notes that&#xA;the increase in TCP is a big thing. At root and typical auths, the use&#xA;of TCP is about 5% and it will go to 50% or higher.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;From the Zoom chat:&lt;br&gt;&#xA;dkg to Everyone (3:48 PM)&lt;br&gt;&#xA;fail-open protocol defaults are terrible long-term. but we currently&#xA;have a open-all-the-time default for recursive-to-authoritative&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Paul Syverson to Everyone (3:48 PM)&lt;br&gt;&#xA;and/or downgrading attacks.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Jim Reid to Everyone (3:49 PM)&lt;br&gt;&#xA;@paul where are the trade-offs documented so informed decisions can be&#xA;made? if there’s no guidance…&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Jim Reid - not compel, but give people good guidance. Where is that to&#xA;happen?&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Paul Hoffman - we tried to do this in DPRIVE, and it became unreadable&#xA;to the operators. Ask Benno to comment: for a lot of operators, the best&#xA;source of information is their vendors.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Benno - Thank you, Paul&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Wes Hardaker - follow-on topic - splitting out secure vs. insecure&#xA;protocols - we should figure out which operators pehaps split TCP vs&#xA;UDP. We (ISI) have created some infrastructure with NSF funding, reach&#xA;out to Wes for help setting up experiments&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Benno - wrapping up, any other last topics&lt;br&gt;&#xA;DKG - I wanted to call out the concerns that Paul Syverson raised about&#xA;fail-open. We are pretty good now at moving form always-open to&#xA;fail-open to something that can be locked down. STS is the example.&#xA;Learn the resource management parts with the opportunistic&#xA;experiments.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Benno - three things to wrap up&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
